hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and if you want my
specialized training to help you
understand native speakers then become a
listening time member and if you want my
advanced podcast episodes then become a
listening time family member ok today
we're going to talk about names this is
a fun topic to talk about especially
with people from different countries
there are many different types of naming
customs around the world
so let's talk a little bit about names
in the u.s
americans usually have three names which
we call the first name middle name and
last name when people get married the
wife usually takes her husband's last
name and then if they have kids their
children take the father's last name
one thing that i want to note is that
there are tons and tons of different
names in the u.s
obviously every country has a wide
variety of names but it seems like in
the u.s there are even more names of
course there are many traditional names
that have been used in english for many
centuries and there are many biblical
names that people give their children
but there are also many non-traditional
these names might come from other
languages or they might be variations of
existing names or they might be names
that the parents invented parents can
get very creative with children's names
nowadays let me talk a little bit about
naming customs in mexico where i live
here people have a first and a middle
name like in the u.s but they have two
last names their first last name is
their father's last name and their
second last name is their mother's last
name
so in general mexican names are longer
than american names or names in other
countries when people get married in
mexico the wife doesn't change her last
name like in the u.s
she keeps both of her last names and
then if they have children their
children take their father's first last
name and their mother's first last name
these two names become their two last
names
so as you can see the naming customs are
pretty different in these two countries
and in other countries around the world
the naming customs might be completely
different from mexico or the us
now let's talk a little bit about
nicknames these are names that people
call other people that aren't their real
names there are certain names in
different languages that have an
accompanying nickname
for example in english people named
robert might be called bob sometimes and
people named matthew might be called
matt and people named william might be
called bill
these are nicknames that are
automatically associated with these
names however many people give more
personal nicknames to their friends or
family members and when people call you
by your nickname it's often a sign that
these people are close with you they
feel more comfortable with you and so
they feel like they can call you by your
nickname i think this is the case in
most countries i had a couple different
nicknames when i was young and i called
some of my friends by their nicknames
how about you do you have a nickname
okay that's all for today remember to
download the listening time podcast and
become a member at patreon.com
listeningtime to receive my specialized
training which will help you understand
native speakers and if you want to reach
an advanced level of listening then
become a listening time family member to
receive my advanced podcast also
subscribe to the channel click on the
bell and follow us on instagram i'll see
you next time